本字幕由 ShinY 深影字幕组原创
时间轴校对：haitaow  特效合并：好汉007
大侦探波罗探案集
第2季第7集 廉价公寓的秘密
快点 警察
Come on, copper.
你要让她吃枪子吗?
Are you gonna let her have it?
已经结束了 波罗 你现在可以睁开眼睛了
It's all over, Poirot. You can open your eyes now.
黑斯廷斯 这是最后一次了
Hastings, this is the last time.
你们两个表现乖一点
You beha ve yourselves, you two.
快点 走吧 你们不能...
Go on, off you go. You stop that...
你也许不喜欢 波罗 但你不能无视它
You might not like it, Poirot, but you can't ignore it.
这是我们生活的一部分 世界的一扇窗户
It's part of our lives, a window on the world.
野蛮人!
Barbaric !
我不在乎这种罪犯
I care not for this type of criminal,
也不在乎美国的侦探们
nor for the detectives of the United States,
他们总是先开枪再问问题
who shoot first and ask the questions later.
啊 拜托 波罗 这又不全是枪战和犯罪团伙
Ah, come on, Poirot, it's not all machine guns and mobsters.
说到罪案调查
In fact when it comes to criminal investigation,
联邦调查局是最棒的
the FBI are second to none.
噢 当然伦敦警察厅例外
Oh, except for Scotland Yard, of course.
好吧 我很快就会让你们知道
Yes well, I 'll let you know soon enough
他们是否名副其实
if they live up to their reputation.
他们给我们派了一个探员过来执行短期任务
They're sending us one of their Agents over on temporary assignment.
我的天啊
Mon Dieu,
这是不是说美国的匪徒们
does that mean that the gangsters of America
打算在伦敦街道上跟踪别人了?
are preparing to stalk the streets of London?
噢 别担心
Oh, no fear.
不 这是间谍案
No, it's a spy case of some kind.
他跟踪一个领导人到了这里
He's following up a lead over here
我必须和他一起工作
and I 've got to work with him.
希望他不会像电影里的布里克・戴维斯先生
I hope he does not take a fter his film counterpart, Monsieur Brick Davis.
对我来说 你朋友帕克先生今晚的派对
For me, the party tonight of your friend, Monsieur Parker,
就已经够让人兴奋了
will be excitement enough.
肯定不会是这个地方
This can't be the place surely.
肯定是出了什么错了
There must ha ve been some kind of mistake.
坎普顿山门
Campden Hill Gate.
一年八十英镑的话 他们肯定是在转租锅炉房
Well, for eighty pounds a year they must be sub letting the boiler room.
五间房的公寓 有所有的现代设备
Five room flat, with all modern conveniences.
六号房间在二楼
Number Six is on the first floor.
走吧 詹姆斯
Come on, James.
让我猜猜 六号房间 那间廉租房吧?
Don't tell me, Number Six, the cheap flat?
别浪费时间了 亲爱的 那间房已经租出去了
Don't waste your time, dear, it's been let.
粗鲁? 我一说出我的名字
And rude? The moment I uttered my name,
他们就把门甩上了
they slammed the door in my face.
斯黛拉...?
Stella...?
也许他们只是不喜欢她的长相
Perhaps they just didn't like the look of her.
晚上好
Good evening.
- 我们听说... - 叫什么?
- We understand... - Name?
罗宾逊
Robinson.
罗宾逊先生和太太 我们希望...
Mr.and Mrs.Robinson, we were hoping...
啊
Ah.
谢谢
Thank you.
那就像是消融的寒霜
It was like a melting frost.
她满脸笑容 领我们进去 带我们参观公寓
All smiles, she ushered us in and we were shown over the flat.
那真是太好了 我们马上就搬进去了
Which was terrific. We're moving in right away.
也许房子闹鬼 或者是凶案现场
Well, perhaps it's haunted. The scene of a grizzly murder.
噢 别这么说!
Oh, don't!
就那个价格 闹鬼也无妨
At that price she can haunt a way.
那我们的侦探朋友呢?
How about our detective friends?
波罗先生 你是专家 你怎么看?
Monsieur Poirot, you're the expert. What do you think?
很不幸 鬼怪一事我并不是专家
Unfortunately, in the matter of ghosts I am no expert.
女士?
Madam?
但确实有两件事很奇怪
But there are two things which are odd, you see.
那间公寓已经打了很长时间的出租广告
The flat had been advertised for some time.
看到这么低的租金 你就会觉得奇怪
Strange when you consider how low the rent was.
你们之前看到广告的时候没有任何疑惑吗?
Well, you'd seen the advertisement before and didn't bother with it.
我们以为是一场骗局
Well, we thought it was a hoax.
其实我们只是出于好奇去的
Eventually we only went out of curiosity.
我们认为既然身在此处...
We thought as we were in the area...
正是 其他人也是这么想的
Precisely. That's just what everyone else thought.
但在我们到访之前
But why was that other woman turned a way
那位女士为什么被拒绝了?
just before we called?
而我们受到了很热烈的欢迎
And yet we were welcomed with open arms.
啊哈...是啊
Aha... yes,
现在 亚瑟 你怎么解释这个?
now, come on, Arthur, how do you get out of that one?
这很明显 不是吗? 她肯定是走错公寓了
Well, it's obvious, isn't it? She must have gone to the wrong flat.
你们看吧 黑斯廷斯上校能解释任何谜团
You see? Captain Hastings can explain every mystery.
谢谢 莱蒙小姐
Thank you, Miss Lemon.
- 早上好 波罗 - 早上好
- Morning, Poirot. - Good morning.
早上好 莱蒙小姐
Morning, Miss Lemon.
波罗先生告诉我你昨晚在泰迪・帕克的派对上
Mr.Poirot has been telling me about your skilful deductions
精彩的推理
at Teddy Parker's party last night.
知道么 波罗 我有时候认为
You know, Poirot, I sometimes think
你没有给我适当的信任
you don't give me credit where it's due.
我知道你觉得这听起来很简单
I know it all sounded rather simplistic to you,
但我只是想表现得圆滑些
but I was merely being tactful.
圆滑?
Tactful?
这很明显 不是吗?
Well, it's obvious, isn't it?
罗宾逊夫妇肯定忽视了合同中的某些东西
The Robinsons have overlooked something in their agreement.
他们很快就会发现是什么了
They'll find out what it is soon enough.
我只希望他们到时不会太震惊
I just hope it doesn't come as too much of a shock.
我知道了
I see.
黑斯廷斯 我很高兴你关心
Well, Hastings, I 'm glad that you show concern
罗宾逊夫妇的问题
for the problem of the Robinsons.
这能让我们的调查更有价值
It will make our enquiries all the more worthwhile.
调查?
Enquiries?
什么调查?
What enquiries?
走吧 黑斯廷斯
Come, Hastings,
趁你还没被埋在赛马的新闻中
before you become buried in the pages of the racing.
我不懂你为什么要把时间浪费在这样的小事上
Can't see why you want to waste your time on such a trivial matter.
黑斯廷斯 你真是让我吃惊
Hastings, you do surprise me.
我很清楚这个案子不像
I am well a ware that this modest case has not the same dramatic appeal
卡格尼先生和他的持枪人那么场面震撼
as the dealings of Monsieur Cagney and his G Men.
虽然这样 这仍是个谜团 值得我们注意
Even so, it is a mystery, and worthy of our attention.
嗯哼
Ahem.
啊
Ah.
谢谢
Thank you.
这个女士认为她能逃脱
So this dame thinks she's headin'for the hand off.
她没想到的是
What she ain't thinking is
负责此案的是联邦探员伯特
Federal Agent Burt is playing for the home team.
有联邦调查局做后盾
And with the FBI quarter backing
又有伦敦警察厅的你们帮忙
and you guys from Scotland Yard running interference,
她连五码都跑不出去
she ain't gonna make five yards,
我们会抓到她的 不是吗?
never mind the touch down. Right?
好的
Right.
我们开始行动吧
Let's move our butts.
好了 伙计们 我们中午再集合
All right lads. We'll reassemble at mid day.
波罗 这是联邦探员伯特
Poirot, this is Federal Agent Burt.
容我向你介绍赫尔克里・波罗 私家侦探
May I introduce Hercule Poirot, the private detective,
还有他的伙伴 黑斯廷斯上校
and his associate, Captain Hastings.
美国的犯罪克星 嗯?
The American crimebuster, eh?
贾普 希望你不是缺人手到要雇佣私家侦探
Japp, I hope you're not so short of manpower you're hiring a Shamus.
他们能有什么用? 追查失踪的狗吗?
What are they good for? Chasing lost dogs.
我们现在面对的是国际安全事件
This is a matter of international security we're dealing with here.
我没打算雇佣任何人 伯特
I ha ve no intention of hiring anyone, Burt.
你要知道 波罗先生很有名气
And if you must know, Mr.Poirot here, has an outstanding reputation.
噢 一个很有名的侦探
Oh, a Gumshoe of distinction.
我想阿尔・卡彭正在竞选总统
And I suppose Al Capone's running for President.
阿尔・卡彭:黑手党教父
嗯 嗯?
Yeah. Yeah?
嗯嗯嗯 那又怎么样?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. So what?
好的 继续努力
All right. So keep tryin'.
噢 你听到了什么?
Oh, you heard what?
听着 朋友 别跟我说兄弟情深的废话
Listen, pal, don't give me this Brotherhood garbage.
这次"横跨大西洋的合作"不如预期那么好?
This''liaison Transatlantique'' does not live up to its expectations?
用专业术语来说 这是一场灾难
Basically, to use a technical term, it's a disaster.
他接管了我的办公室 我的秘书 我的车
He's taken over my office, my secretary, and my car.
现在他要我最棒的手下去监视意大利大使馆
Now he wants my best men to ''stake out''the Italian Embassy.
监视?
''Stake out''?
秘密监视 全天候的
Clandestine surveillance, around the clock.
如果伦敦的地下势力发现
If the London underworld find out that
我部门一半的人都调走了 他们会很高兴的
half my division are tied down, they'll have a field day.
确实 但为什么要监视呢?
Quite so. But why this need for a surveillance?
六个月前 一个小职员从美国海军部
Six months ago, a minor clerk stole the blueprints
偷了一艘新潜水艇的蓝图
for a new submarine from the U.S. Admiralty.
如果东西落入不法人士手中 后果会很严重
There could be serious consequences if they fall into the wrong hands.
这可能成为一场灾难
It could be a catastrophy.
意大利领袖缺少的就是一支强大的海军
The one thing Il Duce lacks is a strong na vy.
正是
Exactly.
很明显 有六艘这样的潜水艇
And apparently with half a dozen of these submarines,
他就能控制地中海
he could control the Mediterranean.
联邦调查局发现一个女人拿到了蓝图
The FBI 's found out that a woman's got the blueprints
她来到了伦敦准备把它卖掉
and she's come to London to sell them.
啊 我现在想起来了
Ah, now I remember,
是不是就是"罗梅罗事件"?
was it not the''Romero Affair''?
胆敢出卖黑手党的美女 嗯?
La Femme Fatale who dared to double cross the Mafia, eh?
她在她事业的某个时候是"金孔雀"吧?
Was she not at some point in her career a''canary''?
金孔雀?
A canary?
是的 你说得对
Yes, that's right.
伴舞乐队歌手
A dance band singer.
伯特先生称她为"花蝴蝶"
What Mr.Burt calls a ''shantoozy''.
天呐!
Good grief !
说真的 黑斯廷斯 你要学着说现代习语!
Really, Hastings, you must try to keep up with the modern idioms, eh !
她现在在这里吗?
And she is here now?
吉姆? 请到我办公室来一下
Jim? Step into my office for a minute, please.
我和奥布莱恩谈过了
I 've had a word with O'Brien,
他在下面的档案室等你
he's expecting you down the Records Office.
抱歉我来迟了 先生
Sorry about the delay, sir,
档案里有好几个罗宾逊
there's a few Robinsons on file.
我们找到的罗宾逊要么"酗酒妨碍治安"
The Robinsons we've got are a''drunk and disorderly'',
要么"袭击神职人员"
an''assault on the member of the clergy'',
要么"故意扔石头毁坏铁路"
and a''throwing stones with intent to do damage to the railway''.
没有斯黛拉或詹姆斯・罗宾逊的记录
Nothing on a Stella, or James Robinson.
看到了吧? 他们是友善的无辜夫妇
You see? They're just a nice innocent couple.
在过去的六个月里
During the last six months,
你是否记得任何案件 哪怕没有解决
can you recall any crime, as yet unsolved,
犯罪的主要嫌疑人是对年轻夫妇的?
where the chief suspects might be a young couple?
我暂时想不到 先生
Nothing comes to mind immediately, sir.
有一对雌雄大盗
There's that Bonnie and Clyde, of course,
但他们逃到了美国中西部的某个地方
but they're at large somewhere in the American Midwest.
希望他们还在那里
And let us hope that is where they remain.
但他们是帕克的朋友
But they're friends of Parker's.
我从念书的时候就认识帕克了
I 've known Parker since we were at school.
他没有罪犯朋友
He doesn't ha ve friends who are criminals.
波罗先生?
Monsieur Poirot?
- 噢 保罗先生 早上好 - 早上好
- Oh, Monsieur Paul, good morning. - Good morning.
这是我的伙伴 黑斯廷斯上校
This is my associate, Captain Hastings.
早上好
Morning.
我们能进去了吗?
Shall we go in?
谢谢
Thank you.
外观很壮丽 不是吗?
Magnificent facade, isn't it?
确实 是我在伦敦见到的最棒的建筑之一
Yes indeed, one of the finest I ha ve seen in London.
保罗先生
Monsieur Paul,
这栋大楼的所有公寓布局都一样吗?
are all the apartments in this block of the same layout?
是的
Yes, exactly.
这是客厅
This is the sitting room.
这是按最高标准设计的
It's been designed to the highest standard.
比方说这是最新的嵌入式电暖炉
Here for example is the latest in inset electric fires.
全嵌入式的 能有自己的选择
Fully built in and with a one or two bar option.
这很有品味 不是吗?
It's very tasteful, don't you think?
确实是的
Yes, indeed.
波罗
Poirot,
你在一间空公寓里查看
you're not going to learn any more about the Robinsons
是不会知道罗宾逊夫妇的任何事的
by looking round an empty flat.
黑斯廷斯 在做出最终决定前
Hastings, it is always wise to make a thorough inspection.
仔细调查总是明智的
before arriving at the final decision.
我不懂你的话
I don't follow you.
黑斯廷斯
Hastings,
我突然想在"坎普顿山门"租一间公寓
I ha ve the sudden desire to take an apartment in Campden Hill Gate.
这间公寓
This apartment.
厨房里装备了最现代化的电器
The kitchen has been equipped with the most modern appliances.
每个架子和橱柜都是量身打造的
Every shelf and cupboard has been discreetly fitted
为的是能给最挑剔的人提供心仪的环境
to provide an environment delightful to even the most particular, of course.
保罗先生 告诉我
Monsieur Paul, tell me,
这个小门有什么用?
for what purpose is this little doorway?
那是放垃圾箱的
It's for the dustbins.
他们一星期从后面的楼梯口那里收两次
They're collected twice weekly from the back stairwell.
啊
Ah.
看来建筑师考虑到了一切便利
It would appear that the architects ha ve thought of every convenience.
你何不好好的仔细看看这个地方呢?
Why don't you examine the place at your leisure?
我会在楼下等你
I 'll wait for you downstairs.
你真是太好了
You are most kind.
不客气 你们慢慢看
Not at all, take your time.
想想这个价格 波罗
Think of the expense, Poirot,
一星期六基尼!
six guineas a week !
啊 但那只是很小的代价 黑斯廷斯
Ah, but that is a small cost, Hastings,
为了追查有大阴谋的谜团
to pursue the mystery of great intrigue.
阴谋?
Intrigue?
有可能这只是件很简单的事
It'll probably turn out to be something perfectly simple.
感动于无家可归的新婚夫妇的困境
Eccentric landlady moved to benevolence
古怪的房主大发善心
by plight of homeless newlyweds.
但是 黑斯廷斯 这不能解释
But this does not explain, Hastings,
为什么这下面的那间廉租房
why the cheap flat below this
打了这么长时间的广告却没人来租
had been advertised for so long and nobody took it.
也许他们发现了有问题
Well, perhaps they all found something wrong with it.
而罗宾逊夫妇没发现?
And the Robinsons did not?
他们看着像易受骗的年轻夫妇吗 黑斯廷斯?
Did they strike you as being the gullible young couple, Hastings?
不 他们不像
No, they didn't.
那我们猜想他们有一些
So we may assume that they possess the special quality
别人没有的特殊品质 不是吗?
that the others were lacking, non?
他们只是一对平常的夫妇
They're just an ordinary couple.
看吧!
Voila!
这就是阴谋所在
There lies the intrigue.
嗯? 你觉得怎么样?
Well? What do you think?
保罗先生 我觉得这间公寓就是我想要的
Monsieur Paul, I think that the apartment is exactly what I want,
我会马上入住的
and I will take possession immediately.
你做了一个聪明的决定
You've made a wise decision.
这些公寓很快就不会供应了
These flats won't be on the market for very long.
就现在的标准来看 租金也很合理
And the rent is very reasonable by today's standard.
出租车!
Taxi !
是的 但不像罗宾逊夫妇的那间那么合理
Yes, but not as reasonable as that of the Robinsons.
噢 你认识罗宾逊夫妇?
Oh, you know the Robinsons?
噢 是的
Oh, yes indeed.
其实 他们刚刚才搬进来 不是吗?
In fact, they ha ve just moved in, is that not so?
罗宾逊夫妇? 六号房间?
The Robinsons? In Number Six?
他们六个月前就搬来了
They moved in six months ago.
那天晚上的派对真不错
Splendid party the other night.
很高兴你能喜欢 老伙计
Glad you en joyed it, old boy.
罗宾逊夫妇看起来很开心
Those Robinsons seemed very pleasant.
你知道他是做什么的吗 罗宾逊先生?
What does he do, do you know, Mr.Robinson?
做什么? 我不太确定
Do? I 'm not sure.
他很久不在镇上了 但是是社会精英
Hasn't been in town long. Salt of the earth, though.
他们是从哪里来的?
Where are they from?
我不知道 镇外的某个地方吧
I don't know. Out of town somewhere.
那你对他们了解多少?
So how do you know them then?
其实 这确实有点奇怪
Well, that was a bit odd, as a matter of fact.
- 是吗? - 是的
- Yes? - Yes.
维罗妮卡和我在剧院
Veronica and I were at the theatre,
我们在中场休息时点了一些饮料
and we'd ordered some drinks for the interval
当我们到那里时 已经有人在喝了
and when we got there, there were these people drinking them.
- 真的吗? - 当然!
- Really? - Absolutely !
好像是我们点了一样的饮料
Well, it seems we'd ordered the same drinks,
我们的标签是六号
our little chitty said Number Six,
他们的是九号 只不过是上下颠倒了
and theirs was Number Nine, only it was upside down.
但还是让我们尴尬了一会
Dashed a wkward for a moment, though.
我知道了
I see.
黑斯廷斯 你迟到了
Hastings, you're late.
我被看门人阻拦了一会
Well, I had a bit of a run in with the Doorman.
我还以为他不会让我进来
Thought he wasn't going to let me into the building.
真的吗?
Really?
好像有个外国人
Well, it seems there's been some foreign fellow
在外面闲晃 打听罗宾逊夫妇的事
hanging around, asking questions about the Robinsons.
那个人不是你吧?
Wasn't you, was it?
当然不是
Certainly not.
也许是监视这间公寓的人
It is probably the man who has been watching the flats.
监视公寓?
Watching the flats?
也许他们不像看起来那么无辜
Maybe they're not as innocent as they seem.
也许他们在进行秘密的进出口生意
Suppose they're tied up in some shady import / export business.
毒品 拐卖妇女
Drugs. White slavery.
黑斯廷斯 你的想象力真是丰富啊
Hastings, you have the most fertile imagination.
没人知道罗宾逊夫妇是从哪来的
Well, nobody seems to know where the Robinsons have come from.
帕克也对他们的事一无所知
Parker doesn't know anything about them at all.
也许他们刚从国外回来
Perhaps they've just returned from abroad.
如果这是真的 黑斯廷斯
If this is true, Hastings,
你很快就有机会弄清楚了
you will soon ha ve the opportunity to find out.
但是现在 我们必须开始工作了
But now please, we must begin our work.
噢 黑斯廷斯
Oh, and Hastings,
请拿上我的手提箱
please bring my valise.
好的
Right.
现在 黑斯廷斯
Now, Hastings,
我要进入罗宾逊夫妇的公寓
I am about to enter the flat of the Robinsons
就从垃圾箱那里走
a fter the method of the dustbins.
你打算闯入他们的公寓?
You're going to break into their flat?
不不不不 不能说是闯入 朋友
No, no, no, no. Not break in precisely, mon ami.
但我必须为今后做准备
But I ha ve to provide for later.
但是 波罗 今天是周六下午 他们肯定在家
But, Poirot, it's Saturday afternoon, they're bound to be at home.
我就是这样希望的 朋友
That is exactly what I am hoping, mon ami,
因为你要去扮演一个
because you are about to play the role of
正好路过的友好邻居
the friendly neighbour who just happens to be passing by.
我在进行任务的时候 希望你帮我拖住他们
I want you to keep the young couple occupied while I perform my task.
等他们出去了 这事不是更简单吗?
Well, wouldn't it be easier to wait until they go out?
黑斯廷斯 这些事我已经考虑过了
Hastings, these are things I ha ve already considered.
他们出门的时候 这个门总是锁着的
While they are out, the doorway, it is always locked.
那我要说什么?
What am I going to say?
黑斯廷斯上校 请进
Captain Hastings. Do come in.
啊 黑斯廷斯!
Ah, Hastings!
什么风把你吹到这里来了?
What brings you to this neck of the woods?
你问我的话
If you ask me,
是侦探的好奇本能让他过来拜访的
the natural curiosity of the private investigator has prompted this visit.
不 不是的
No, not at all.
其实我在布朗普顿路有生意
In fact I had some business to attend to in the Brompton Road,
当我想起你们就住在附近
and when I remembered you were living nearby,
我突然想到
I suddenly thought,
罗宾逊夫妇 他们肯定知道
''The Robinsons, of course they're bound to know. ''
我是应该用獾毛
Now, should I use badger hair,
还是用普通的刷子就行?
or will an ordinary brush do the trick?
什么?
I 'm sorry?
我想给人留下的印象是
Well, what I want is a sort of impression
有纹理 但又不能太明显
of graininess without it being too obvious.
我不想看起来有棱有角的
I don 't want it to look ridgy.
我是说有时候看来确实有棱有角的 不是吗?
I mean it sometimes does look ridgy, doesn 't it?
我非常不赞成那样
I 'm dead set against that.
马毛 猪毛 或者獾毛
horsehair, hog bristle, or badger hair.
当然 一把好的织补梳也有这样的效果
And apparently a fine steel comb produces the same effect,
不过最好是在墙上或地板上 更轮廓分明
only it's better on walls and floors, more defined.
黑斯廷斯上校
Captain Hastings,
一个人要獾毛和织补梳做什么呢?
what would one be doing with badger hair and a steel comb?
噢 我没说过吗?
Oh, didn't I say?
磨平和梳理
''Dragging and Combing''.
你知道它对木工活的效果有多好吗?
You know what a fine effect it creates on woodwork?
不过我不是装修的内行人
Only, I 'm not exactly a dab hand when it comes to decorating,
所以我想我应该来向你们寻求专家意见
so I thought I 'd call on you for an expert opinion.
当我在法国用木馏油处理它的时候
when I creosoted the dug out in France,
但不像你们做的工作那样
but not like you with all the work you 've done.
黑斯廷斯 我们什么都没做 我们昨天才搬来
Hastings, we ha ven't done a thing, we only moved in yesterday.
我必须承认 我根本不知道
And I have to admit, I wouldn't know
一把獾毛刷和一桶炖牛肉有什么不同
a badger hair brush from a bucket of beef stew.
噢 你真是太谦虚了
Oh, you're too modest.
我相信你们在意大利期间 一定受到了
I 'm sure you were both influenced by the spirit of the Renaissance
复兴思想的影响
during your time in Italy.
意大利?
Italy?
你怎么会这么想?
Whatever ga ve you that idea?
不是帕克说你们刚从欧洲回来吗?
Didn 't Parker say you 'd just returned from the Continent?
詹姆士获得了伦敦互保公司的职位
when James was offered a position at London Mutual.
我们从没去过欧洲
We 've never been on the Continent.
保险公司
Insurance.
其实 我一直在想给我的车采用新的政策
In fact, I 've been thinking about taking out a new policy on my car.
那到底是什么声音?
What on earth was that?
是从厨房传来的
It came from the kitchen.
我什么都没听到
I didn't hear anything.
我还是去看一下好了
I 'd better take a look.
让我来吧 这是侦探的特权
Allow me. Detective's prerogative.
谁知道呢 说不定是鬼呢
You never know, it might be one of the ghosts.
我猜应该是风吹开的
Wind blew it open, I expect.
如果是我的话 我会把这里栓上的
I should keep this bolted, if I were you.
谁都不知道附近有些什么人
You never know who's about.
我不知道罗宾逊夫妇会怎么说
I don't know what the Robinsons would have said
如果他们看到了赫尔克里・波罗
if they'd seen the foot of Hercule Poirot
消失在了楼梯间的暮光之中
disappearing into the twilight of the back stairwell.
我很感激你的快速思维 朋友
I am indebted to your quick thinking, mon ami.
我不认为罗宾逊夫妇有隐瞒什么
I can't believe the Robinsons ha ve anything to hide.
如果说有人举止可疑的话
If anyone's beha ving in a suspicious manner
也应该是把房子租给他们的那个女人
it's that woman who let the flat to them.
但是 你不觉得奇怪吗 朋友
But did it not strike you as odd, mon ami,
房产代理人对罗宾逊太太的描述
that the estate agent's description of Madame Robinson
与我们认识的罗宾逊太太迥然不同?
was so very different from the Madame Robinson that we know?
也许他不太善于观察
Not the most observant of fellows.
也许她们不是同一个罗宾逊太太 嗯?
Perhaps they are different Madame Robinsons, eh?
也许他的罗宾逊太太等了很久
Perhaps his Madame Robinson had been waiting a long time
才等到一个同名的转租人?
to find a subtenant of the same name?
她为什么要这样做呢?
Why on earth would she do that?
这太奇怪了
That's strange,
那个园丁长得真像贾普的手下 达尔崔警官
that gardener's a dead ringer for Japp's man, Sergeant Daltry.
你的眼睛并没有骗你 朋友 这里
Your eyes, they do not deceive you, mon ami. Here.
如果我没弄错的话
If I am not mistaken,
这辆车就是贾普总探长监视意大利大使馆的
this van is the nerve centre of Inspector Japp's stake out
控制中心
at the Italian Embassy.
你们俩在这做什么?
What are you two doing here?
我们碰巧路过 而且...
Well it happens that we were passing by and...
我觉得有必要满足一下黑斯廷斯的好奇心
well, it is necessary to satisfy the curiosity of Hastings.
波罗!
Poirot !
趁没人看见 你们赶快进来
You'd better come inside before somebody sees you.
看吧 所有出口都被前后包围了
So look, all the exits are covered front and back,
我们还有几辆便衣警车
and we ha ve a couple of unmarked cars
在路边候命 以防她逃跑
just standing by in case she decides to take it on the lam.
不管怎样 只要卡拉・罗梅罗一现身
Whichever way, as soon as Carla Romero shows up,
我们就能抓住她
we're ready to nab her.
真是不错的布局啊 伯特先生
A well staged operation, Mr.Burt.
很荣幸我能帮上忙
Glad I could be of some help.
那个男人是谁?
Who is that man?
噢 他一直进进出出的
Oh, he's in and out all the time.
我猜应该是个遇到麻烦的旅客
Some tourist in trouble, I guess.
如果卡拉・罗梅罗一直不出现呢?
Suppose Carla Romero never comes, eh?
如果她派了其他人呢?
Suppose she sends someone else?
好吧 作为一个私家侦探 你会怎么做 嗯?
All right, as a Private Dick, what would you do, huh?
直接走出去 让他在蓝图现身时联系我们?
Just walk right in there, and ask him to call us when the blueprints show up?
我会把精力集中在寻找卡拉・罗梅罗上
I would concentrate my efforts on trying to find Carla Romero.
她是个年轻的迷人的美国人
She is a young, attractive American,
还是孤身旅行 她会是个非常可疑的人
and tra velling alone, she would be a figure most conspicuous.
她也许是一个人
Alone she might.
但我们知道她和一个同伙同行
But we know she's travelling with an accomplice.
伯特先生 我听说她和黑手党有交易?
Monsieur Burt, I understand that she has had some dealings with the Mafia?
你们什么时候才能懂呢?
When will you guys understand?
根本没有
There is no such thing
黑手党这回事
as the Mafia, or the Black Hand or the Cosa Nostra.
是的 有一些从南欧来的移民家族
Sure, there's some immigrant families of mainly Southern European extraction
他们彼此较劲 但是有计划的犯罪?
who push each other around, but organised crime?
不 先生
No, sir.
不
No.
不 谢谢你 但是...
No, thank you, but...
是的 我肯定她是的
Yes, I 'm sure that she is.
是的 但是这并没有关系
Yes, but you see that is of no interest.
不 真的没有关系 什么都没有
No. No interest at all. None whatsoever.
但还是谢谢你 是的
But thank you. Yes.
再见
Goodbye.
黑斯廷斯 我已经给十四家夜总会打了电话
Hastings, I ha ve telephoned fourteen night clubs.
有八家有"花蝴蝶" 但没有一个是美国人
Eight of them ha ve the ''shantoozies'', but none of them American.
三家有男低音
Three of them have the male crooners,
一家有魔术师 一家有钢琴师
one of them has a magician, one a pianist,
还有"黑猫夜总会"不接电话
and the Black Kat won't answer the telephone.
你在找什么?
What are you looking for?
试想一下 黑斯廷斯
Suppose, Hastings,
卡拉・罗梅罗等着把这些文件卖掉时
that Carla Romero is forced to return to her old trade
她被逼重操旧业为生?
to support her while she is waiting to sell those documents?
我觉得有可能啊
Well it's possible, I suppose.
你怎么突然对卡拉・罗梅罗这么感兴趣了?
Why are you so interested in Carla Romero all of a sudden?
为什么不让联邦调查局自己解决这个案子呢?
Why not let the F.B.I. solve their own cases?
但也许确实和罗宾逊夫妇有联系
But there is a connection perhaps, with the Robinsons.
我看到的那个进入意大利大使馆的人
The man that I sa w entering the Italian Embassy
就是那个监视他们公寓的人
is the same man who has been watching their apartment.
你没觉得这很有趣吗 黑斯廷斯?
And do you not find it intriguing, Hastings,
唯一没接电话的夜总会就是"黑猫"?
that the only club who did not answer the telephone was the Black Kat?
下午好 请问 经理在吗?
Good afternoon. I wonder, could you tell me, please, is the manager here?
在后面
Back there.
谢谢
Thank you.
你真好
Most kind.
稍等 是谁啊?
Just a minute. Who is it?
赫尔克里・波罗
Hercule Poirot.
再说一遍?
Come again?
波罗 你是?
Poirot. And you?
我没什么好隐瞒的
I 've got nothing to hide.
伯尼・科尔 请进
Bernie Cole. Come in.
谢谢
Thank you.
大家都认识我 伯尼・科尔 夜总会之王
Everyone knows me, anyway. Bernie Cole, King of the Clubs.
你以前没有经常过来听我们的歌吧?
Didn't you used to come down to the old Caprice?
没有
No.
那你前来有何贵干?
What are you a fter, then anyway?
希望不是违法的事
Nothing, illicit, I trust.
不 当然不是
No, certainly not.
噢
Oh.
抱歉 先生 那下面的不是电话吗?
Pardon, monsieur, but is that not the telephone under there?
不是
No.
好吧 是的 都快把人逼疯了 不是吗?
Well, yes. Drives you mad, doesn't it?
某个人吧!
Some people !
先生 艾尔莎・哈特女士在这里唱歌 是吗?
Monsieur, Mademoiselle Elsa Hart is singing here, is she not?
是谁想知道?
Who wants to know?
外面有一张海报!
There is a poster outside!
不 我想知道的是
No, what I want to know is,
艾尔莎・哈特是美国人吗?
is it Elsa Hart, the American?
不是
No.
我曾经在纽约听过她的大名
I heard her in New York once, you understand.
噢 是吗? 她是加拿大人 就像那些五胞胎
Oh, yes? She's Canadian. Like those Dionne quintuplets.
很快就会风靡一时的 加拿大
It's going to be all the rage soon, Canada.
我们很快就会有这个加拿大人 那个加拿大人
We'll ha ve Canadian this, Canadian that.
伯尼・科尔总是能发现流行趋势
Bernie Cole can always spot a trend.
我就是以此出名
Known for it.
我知道你在听!
I know you're there !
但如果经理说她是加拿大人...
But if the Manager says she's Canadian...
她当然会这么跟他说 黑斯廷斯
But of course she would tell him that, Hastings.
她偷走了蓝图 她的敌人正在找她
She has stolen the blueprints. Her enemies are pursuing her.
她改了名字 为何不把国籍也改了呢?
She changes her name. Why not also, her nationality?
是啊 我也这么认为
Yes, I suppose so.
虽然她很谨慎
Then, in spite of all her precautions,
她还是发现有人追踪到了她
she discovers that someone has tracked her down.
所以她决定离开自己的公寓
So, she decides to leave her own apartment
再安排一个和她同名的人入住
and to install someone of the same name.
罗宾逊夫妇
The Robinsons.
你是说女房东把他们当做诱饵?
Well, you mean the landlady is using them as a decoy?
是的 朋友
Yes, mon ami.
慷概的女房东
The charitable landlady,
鬼鬼祟祟的间谍 也许还有歌手艾尔莎・哈特
the devious agent of espionage and perhaps also the singer, Elsa Hart,
肯定是同一个人
are surely one and the same.
我以为我的想象力就够丰富了
I thought I was the one with the fertile imagination,
这太不可思议了
this is fantastic.
不 黑斯廷斯
No, Hastings,
这是一场罪恶的阴谋
this is a plot of sinister dimensions.
罗宾逊夫妇会成为刺杀行动的对象
The Robinsons are to be the victims of a ruthless assassin.
晚上好
Good evening.
我是"妇女协会"的佩内洛普・梅特兰
Penelope Maitland, from''The Lady's Companion'',
我早些时候留了口信的
I sent a note round earlier.
啊 是啊 你真好 请进
Ah yes. Very nice, too. Please come in.
你为什么不接电话呢?
Why do you never answer your telephone?
如今总是接到扰人的电话 不是吗?
You get all these nuisance calls these days, don't you?
友情提示您一下 亲爱的
A friendly word of warning, my dear.
她对这个主意并不上心
She wasn't keen on the idea.
她看上去可能有点冷淡
She may seem a bit frosty,
就把这当做是艺术家气质吧
put it down to artistic temperament.
我想在你的工作中
I 'm sure you're used to dealing
你一定习惯了面对各种各样的人?
with all sorts of people in your line of business?
是的
Yes, indeed.
顺着走廊直走 左边第二间 祝您好运
Straight down the corridor, second on the left. Good luck.
稍后过来找我喝一杯吧
Come and see me afterwards for a drink.
艾尔莎・哈特小姐在吗?
Miss Elsa Hart?
有事吗?
Yes?
我是"妇女协会"的佩内洛普・梅特兰
Penelope Maitland from the''Lady's Companion. ''
请进吧
Why don't you come in?
噢 你的节目还有"百老汇摇篮曲"
Oh, I see your repertoire includes ''Lullaby of Broadway,''
这是我最喜欢的节目之一
it's one of my own favourites.
真的吗? 很高兴你能喜欢
Really? Glad you like it.
梅特兰小姐
Now, Miss Maitland,
为什么...呃...
why would the readers of the uh...
..."妇女协会"的读者
...'Lady's Companion''.
是啊
Right.
为什么有人想看一个夜总会歌手的新闻呢?
Why would anyone want to read about a night club singer?
是魅力和浪漫因子 哈特小姐
It's the glamour and the romance, Miss Hart.
一个现代女人的形象
The image of the modern woman.
现在
Now.
我听说你才来英国不久?
I understand you've only been in England a short time?
她说过去九个月她和她的丈夫
So she says she has been touring the capital cities of Europe
游历了欧洲各国的首都?
with her husband for the past nine months?
是的 在各种各样的夜总会工作
Yes, working in a variety of night clubs.
但我们勇敢的记者并不相信 嗯?
But our intrepid journalist was not convinced, eh?
任何一个声称在布洛涅森林
Anyone who claims to have been stag hunting
猎鹿的人 波罗先生
in the Bois de Boulogne, Mr.Poirot,
对欧洲生活的理解都大错特错了
has been seriously misinformed about life on the Continent.
真了不起!
Extraordinaire !
还有其他的发现吗?
There was something more?
在她的更衣室有一本歌曲剧目
There was a songsheet in her dressing room.
是去年一月份美国出版的
An American publication dating back to last January.
我有可靠的根据
I ha ve it on good authority,
这在美国境外是买不到的
it isn't obtainable outside the United States.
它只可能是在美国境内买的
It could only ha ve been obtained in America.
莱蒙小姐
Miss Lemon,
我相信"妇女协会"新招的员工
I believe that the newest recruit of the''Lady's Companion''
抢到大新闻了
has made a scoop.
已经过了午夜了
It's gone midnight.
我们还要等多久?
How long are we going to wait?
必要的话要等一整晚 朋友
All night if necessary, mon ami.
恐怕你没法美美睡上一觉了
I am a fraid you may lose your beauty sleep.
反正我是不会眨眼的
I wouldn't get a wink anyway
要弄清这次间谍活动中谁是谁
trying to fathom out who's who in this espionage business.
这事并不正大光明
It is a devious affair.
罗梅罗一开始是怎么偷到文件的?
How did Romero manage to steal the documents in the first place?
卡拉・罗梅罗并不是个小偷 朋友
Carla Romero was not a thief, mon ami,
而是个引诱男人的人
but a temptress.
黑斯廷斯 我给你讲个小故事
Hastings, I will recount to you the little history.
这个故事会让你想起你最喜欢的电影院
It is a story that will remind you of your favourite cinema.
首先
To begin,
我们必须回到六个月前的纽约东边
we ha ve to go back six months to the East Side of New York,
臭名昭著的卡拉・罗梅罗在那里的
where the notorious Carla Romero
一家夜总会当歌手
was working as a singer in a night club.
#我会跋涉千山万水#
#I 'd make a million trips...#
#来到他的唇边#
#to his lips#
#如果我是一只蜜蜂#
#If I were a Bee#
#因为对我而言#
#'Cause they are sweeter than...#
#他们比任何糖果都甜#
#any candy to me#
#他是...#
#He 's granulated #
#砂糖#
# Sugar#
#我从不欺骗...#
#I never cheat on #
#我的甜心#
# my Sugar#
#因为我的甜心#
#'Cause I 'm too sweet #
#已足够甜#
# on my Sugar#
#我的...#
#that Sugar baby #
#甜心#
# of mine#
#我的甜心#
#I 'm too sweet on that #
#已足够甜#
# Sugar baby of mine.#
她发现并引诱了一个年轻的
She had sought out and seduced a young clerk
美国海军部的职员
in the American Department of the Na vy.
他的名字叫做路易吉・瓦尔达诺
His name was Luigi Valdarno.
我的歌怎么样?
How did it go?
就像从孩子手中拿走糖果一样
Like taking candy from a baby.
我会准备好 十分钟后在大门见
I 'll get ready and meet you out front in ten minutes.
他深深被这个女人迷惑
He was so besotted with this siren,
说服他从美国海军部
that persuading him to steal the secret papers
偷走秘密文件很容易
from the U.S. Na vy was an easy task.
瓦尔达诺不知道的是
Unknown to Valdarno,
这个邪恶计划里卡拉・罗梅罗的同谋
the accomplice of Carla Romero in this sinister plot
就是她的丈夫
was her husband.
那个晚上
That same night,
瓦尔达诺开车载卡拉・罗梅罗
Valdarno drove Carla Romero
去了一个废弃的码头
to a deserted wharf,
他相信她已经在那里
where he believed she had arranged a rendezvous
约好和一位意大利政府官员见面
with an Agent of the Italian Government.
新的美国潜水艇的蓝图
The blueprints for the new American submarine
将会换到五十万美元
would be exchanged for half a million dollars.
这就是了 亲爱的 轻轻的慢慢的把它拿过去
This is it, baby, take it nice and slow.
路易吉
Luigi,
你把事情想得太简单了
you made it all too easy.
卡拉 不
Carla, no.
再见了 我的小情人
Goodbye, lover boy.
我们离开这里吧
Let's get out of here.
他们接到的命令是把蓝图
Their instructions had been to deliver the blueprints
交给他们组织里的联络人
to the contact in the Brotherhood.
但是罗梅罗和她丈夫有更好的主意
But Romero and her husband had a better idea.
没有把文件交给她在黑手党里的主人
Instead of passing the documents to her masters in the Mafia,
卡拉・罗梅罗和她丈夫
Carla Romero and her husband,
化名为罗宾逊飞过了大西洋
fled across the Atlantic under the name of Robinson
把卖文件的钱据为己有
to sell the documents for their own gain.
然后他们发现有人要来刺杀他们
Then they discovered they had an assassin on their trail.
是的
Yes.
卡拉・罗梅罗的背叛激怒了黑手党
The deception of Carla Romero so infuriated the Ma fia
他们的荣誉让他们展开了报复
that their Code of Honour would demand revenge.
准备好 勇士
Prepare yourself, mon brave.
我们的访客来了
Our visitor has arrived.
慢一点 黑斯廷斯
Slowly, Hastings,
我们必须像教堂的老鼠一样安静
we must be as quiet as the chapel mouse.
我还是觉得让罗宾逊夫妇撤退更安全
I still think it would ha ve been sa fer to evacuate the Robinsons.
这样做会打草惊蛇
To do so would ha ve created the unnecessary attention.
如果他们像我所想的那么无辜
If they are as innocent as I suspect,
他们什么都不知道反而更好
it would be better that they know nothing of this.
他正在撬前门的锁
He's picking the lock on the front door.
黑斯廷斯 把你的枪给我
Hastings, pass me your revolver.
按计划就位
Take up your position as planned.
嘿!
Allez!
黑斯廷斯 枪!
Hastings, the gun !
小心 黑斯廷斯
Be careful, Hastings.
快追
Allonsy.
没看到人 波罗 这真是一场灾难
Nowhere to be seen. Poirot, this is a disaster.
别担心 朋友 他今晚不会回来了
Well, do not worry, mon ami. He will not return here tonight.
我们年轻的朋友们安全了
Our young friends are sa fe.
现在 我们该去认识一下难以捉摸的
But now it is time to make our acquaintance with the elusive
卡拉・罗梅罗了
Carla Romero.
黑斯廷斯 波罗
Hastings, Poirot.
总探长 伯特先生
Chief Inspector, Monsieur Burt.
好了 走吧
All right, let's go.
快点 伙计们
Come on, lads.
#我可以成为国王 亲爱的 只是没有王冠#
#I could be a king, dear, uncrown 'd#
#无论贫穷还是富有 卑微还是出名#
#Humble or poor, rich or renown 'd#
晚上好 波罗先生
Evening, Mr.Poirot.
晚上好 科尔先生
Good evening, Monsieur Cole.
你真是来得悄无声息啊
You're a quiet one.
帮我给总探长说几句好话 嗯?
Put in a good word for me with the Chief Inspector, eh?
别担心 科尔先生
Have no fear, Monsieur Cole.
你看 伯特探员
You see, Agent Burt,
有时候 走失的狗就在这么一个明显的地方
sometimes the lost dog can be found in a place so conspicuous
人们反而想不到
it is the last to be considered.
你最好是对的 波罗 不然我就要去阿拉斯加
You'd better be right, Poirot, or I 'll be the one chasing lost dogs...
找走失的狗了
in Alaska.
我们可以相信波罗先生的灰色细胞 伯特先生
I think we can rely on Mr.Poirot's little grey cells, Burt.
她在唱最后一首歌了 总探长
She's performing her last song now, Chief Inspector.
希望如此 科尔先生
Let's hope so, Mr.Cole.
她一下舞台 我希望你马上把这里清空
As soon as she lea ves the stage, I want you to clear the building.
你可以相信我 总探长
You can depend on me, Chief.
那就是卡拉・罗梅罗
That's Carla Maria Romero all right.
我们去抓她吧
Let's tackle her.
你以为你在做什么?
What do you think you're playing at?
你不能拿着枪到处晃! 把枪给我
You can't go wa ving guns about! Give that to me.
你开玩笑呢吧?
Are you kidding me?
把枪给我 否则行动取消
You just give that to me or the whole operation's off.
没人会相信的
Nobody's gonna believe this.
想什么呢!
The idea !
把枪收好 警官
Look a fter this, Constable.
#只要有你#
#There 's just nothing I couldn 't do #
#我没什么做不到#
# If I had you...#
#只要有你#
#There 's just nothing I couldn 't do #
# 我没什么做不到#
# If I had you...#
好了
Right.
噢 不 你先请
Oh, no, please a fter you.
我待在后面打下手就行了
I 'll just stay in the background with my knitting.
什么事?
Yeah?
啊 哈特小姐
Ah, Mademoiselle Hart.
我就知道能在这找到你
I had hoped to find you here.
先生
Monsieur.
这是你的仰慕者的代表吗?
This a deputation of your admirers, or something?
啊 某种程度上来说 是的
Ah well, in a way, yes.
哈特小姐 你的声音真的很好听
Mademoiselle Hart. Indeed, you ha ve a fine voice.
我们就这样吗?
Can we just do this?
冷静 冷静
All right, all right.
女歌手的生活很精彩 嗯?
And the life of the chanteuse, is a glamorous one, eh?
我们是要把她说死吗?
Are we gonna talk her to death or what?
但你真正的天赋 小姐
But your real talents, mademoiselle,
狡诈和欺骗 更加费力 不是吗?
the cunning and deception are far more taxing, non?
你以为你在这里做什么?
What do you think you're doing here?
这是派对还是什么?
Is this a party or something?
是的 告别派对 亲爱的
Yeah, a farewell party, sweetie.
哈特小姐
Mademoiselle Hart,
或是应该叫你卡拉・罗梅罗
or do you prefer to be called Carla Romero,
又或者甚至是罗宾逊太太?
or perhaps even Madame Robinson?
知道有人要刺杀你
With an assassin on your trail,
你让另一对罗宾逊夫妇住进了你的公寓
you substituted the other Robinsons into your flat.
你真的很聪明
You have been very clever.
但有一件事我想知道 女士
But there is one thing I must know, madame.
是你第一个意识到
Was it you who first realised
瓦尔达诺在海军部的位置的重要性吗?
the value of Valdarno's position at the Department of the Na vy?
是的
Yeah,
主意都是我出的 他们只会拿钱
I had all the big ideas. They just palmed all the greenbacks.
像你这么聪明的女人不可能
And there could never be a position for a woman of your ingenuity
在黑手...
in the Ma...
抱歉 在你的组织里得到职位?
Pardon. In the Brotherhood?
组织?
Brotherhood?
听着 联邦调查局对这个说得很清楚
Look, the F.B.I. is unequivocal in this matter.
根本没有什么该死的组织!
There is no such thing as the goddam Brotherhood !
噢 是啊 你认为你能操控整个世界 嗯?
Oh, yeah, so you thought you 'd just take on the whole world, huh ?
这就是你的末路了 女士
Well it's the end of the road for you, lady.
你现在何不交出蓝图 我们就都能回家了
So why don't you just hand over the blueprints now and we can all go home.
华盛顿方面会很高兴拿回它的
Washington will be glad to get this back.
好了 走吧 你也是
Right, move it. You too.
你以为你可以杀死路易吉 然后出卖黑手党?
You thought you could kill Luigi and double cross the Cosa Nostra?
你错了 女人
Well, you was wrong, sister.
现在我们要扳回一局
Now we're gonna settle the score.
噢 这真是太好了 只有他才有枪!
Oh, this is good. Everybody's got a heater except the good guys !
你就打算站在那里 让他开枪打死我吗?
Are you just gonna stand there and let him shoot me?
那是我的枪 波罗!
That's my gun, Poirot!
不不不 朋友
No, no, no, mon ami,
我没时间浪费给这个所谓的美国犯罪团伙
I ha ve no time for these so called mobsters of America.
我已经见过很多这样的闹剧了
I ha ve seen enough of this charade.
再动一步 就要说晚安了
One a'more a move, its goodnight.
晚安 终于结束了!
Good night and good riddance!
这是个有名望的夜总会
This is a respectable club.
再见 卡拉
Arriverderci, Carla.
黑斯廷斯 你总不相信我 嗯?
So, Hastings, never will you trust your old friend, eh?
继续走
Keep walking.
我们在罗宾逊夫妇的公寓里时
I took the precaution to remove the bullets
我就提前拿走了子弹
while we were in the apartment of the Robinsons.
你怎么知道他会跟踪我们到这里?
How did you know he'd follow us here?
我们离开坎普顿山门时 刺客在暗处埋伏
Ah, well when we left Campden Hill Gate, the assassin was lying in wait.
我提到我们约好和卡拉・罗梅罗见面
I mentioned our rendezvous with Carla Romero,
所以他肯定会跟着来的
so that he would be sure to follow.
伯特探员
So Agent Burt,
我们一箭双雕了 嗯?
we ha ve killed both the birds with one shot, eh?
啊 一箭都没射呢
Ah. And without firing a single shot.
谁都不可能逃过国家的制裁
It's no way to run a country.
你说这个犯罪组织
So, you say this association of criminals
派了一个杀手来追杀罗梅罗小姐 嗯?
sent a hit man a fter Miss Romero, eh?
是的 但她打算用她以前公寓里
Yes, but she had planned to deceive him
和她同名的夫妇来骗过他
by installing the young couple of the same name in her old apartment.
那枪的把戏又是怎么回事 波罗?
And what about your joke with the gun, Poirot?
啊 总探长
Ah, well, Inspector,
你和黑斯廷斯上校都很喜欢悬念
you and Captain Hastings are so fond of the suspense,
我怎么禁得住诱惑
how could I resist the temptation
不把这个案子推上高潮呢?
to bring this intriguing case to the most dramatic climax?
波罗先生
Well, Mr.Poirot,
我真的该和你握个手
I 've really got to hand it to you.
你真是太好了 先生
You are most kind, monsieur.
我肯定 美国政府
And the U.S. Government, I 'm sure,
会为你的努力而嘉奖你的
would like to reward you for all your efforts.
海军部永远欠你的情
The Na vy will always be in your debt.
茶准备好了 在厨房里 希望你们不介意
Tea's ready. In the kitchen, if you don't mind.
你真是太好了
That's terribly kind of you.
一伙窃贼洗劫了整栋大楼?
A gang of burglars working the whole building?
真是太不可思议了
Quite extraordinary.
你们能抓到他们吗?
Do you expect to catch them?
恐怕不能 太太 他们是专业犯罪团伙
Unfortunately not, madam, they were a professional outfit.
他们会留个人放风
They would ha ve had a man on watch.
等我们到的时候 他们早走了
By the time we arrived, they were gone.
我们应该庆幸什么都没丢
I suppose we should be grateful nothing was stolen.
我们还应该感谢黑斯廷斯上校的警觉性
And we should thank Captain Hastings for his vigilance.
因为如果他没有注意到
Because if he had not noticed that
通往垃圾箱的门被撬了...
the door for the dustbins had been tampered with...
嘿
I say,
看这个...
look at this...
这真的是专业的作案工具
Now there's a real professionals' tool, if ever I sa w one.
嗯 把这个留下真是太不小心了
Mmm. And very careless to lea ve it behind, if you ask me.
也许我应该验验这上面的指纹?
Perhaps I should ha ve it checked for fingerprints?
你什么都不会发现的 总探长
You will find nothing, Chief Inspector.
专业的作案分子
For the real professional,
都是戴手套作案的
he wears the gloves.